## Arturo Jain

### Web developer

Lomas de Angelopolis III, 72850, Santa Clara Ocoyucan, Puebla MX

http://arturojain.com arturo.jaindo@udlap.mx +52 1 (222) 215 4541

🔾 arturojain 🄰 arturojain in arturojain arturojain M arturojain



I devoted my life to media, content creation, and community management using low-budget technologies, achieving and exceeding my established — and own — goals. My experience has grown overtime by working in several projects gaining knowledge in design, marketing, photography, and my bachelor as an IT and systems engineer.

#### **SKILLS**

### Web development

java | css | html | javascript | node.js | angular.js | jquery | json | xml | php | heroku | bootstrap | auth0 | conekta.js | cloudflare | aws s3 | sparkpost | mailchimp api | express.js | javascript standard style | sass | jade | papertrail | moment.js

### **Project managment**

git | github | asana | basecamp | slack | wunderlist | mixpanel

### Design

web design | ui design | ux design | adobe creative suite | photography | video post-production

#### **Database**

database design | mysql | microsoft sql server | postgresql | redis

#### Communication

intercultural communication | language teaching | translation | interpretation | public speaking

### **Engineering**

extremexos fundamentals | ios 8 app development essentials

#### Other

dgi plotters | led lighting systems | piano interpretation | happyfox chat

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Developer at io media, S.A. de C.V.

June 2015 - Current

https://iomedia.mx

Development of web platforms, design of digital communication and IT administration.

- Universidad de las Américas Puebla (UDLAP)
- TEDxUDLAP
- Salutem, Centro de Especialidades Médicas
- Grupo Proactivo Mexicano

## Internship at T-Systems Mexico

April 2014 - May 2015

http://www.t-systems.com.mx

Creation of the web platforms Innova-T, platform to promote the innovation in the employees with the creation and generation of ideas and projects using a voting (liking) system to promote the best ideas or projects, and GIS, web app to book meeting rooms and invite guests to the meeting, support of the Innovation area as UX designer.

- Development of both the Innova-T platform and the GIS platform. Both were platforms that had not been developed for over two years prior to my arrival and were deployed and developed in record time. The GIS app is an app that reduces cost to the company due to the lack of need of people to book meeting rooms, previously done by the Service Desk.
- Web development using Java Web, jQuery, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and MySQL. UX design, designing the UI for GIS, Innova-T, Localiza-T and more.

## **Trainee** at Signlight Mexico

#### February 2014 - May 2015

#### http://signlight.com.mx

Website development, consultancy in information technology and communication, English-Spanish translation and oral interpretation.

- Web development, English-Spanish translation and oral interpretation in countries like South Korea and the United States.
- English-Spanish translation and oral interpretation, web design, web development, knowledge of information and communication technologies applied in business.

### Trainee at NP Lighting Gruppe GmbH

#### January 2012 - December 2013

Website development, consultancy in information technology and communication, English-Spanish translation and oral interpretation.

- Web development, English-Spanish translation and oral interpretation in countries like South Korea and the United States
- English-Spanish translation and oral interpretation, web design, web development, knowledge of information and communication technologies applied in business.

#### **Editor in Chief** at Revista DiGGital

#### January 2010 - December 2012

Design strategies to reach more monthly readers. Monitor the published content and establish the strategy of the blog. Connect with companies and events in order to get new or exclusive information to our readers.

- 40K+ monthly readers. Connections with events like Aldea Digital, Campus Party and the Electronic Game Show (EGS) in Mexico. Creation of a UI that the user loved and worked as needed.
- Web development, social media strategies, CMS implementation, UI design, project management, resource allocation, public speaking and writing/publishing abilities.

## Community manager at Halo Mexico / Gaming Mexicano Profesional

October 2008 - December 2010

Creating and producing live video streaming, video content and engaging the community in brand.

- Developing a professional live video stream with a very low budget. Engaging a community of 1.1K+ people to a new brand. Implementing new technologies to help communicate, control and engage the community.
- Video production, live video stream production, event production, community management, technolo- gies consultancy and expertise.

#### **VOLUNTEER**

## **Information and Communication Technologies**

at Sustenta, Centro de Responsabilidad Social

August 2014 - May 2015

http://centrosustenta.org.mx

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor Engineering** at Universidad de las Americas Puebla (UDLAP) 2011 - 2016

## High School High School at Universidad la Salle Mexico (ULSA)

2008 - 2011

# **TEDxUDLAP Co-organizer** at TED Conferences, LLC 2016

# **TEDxUDLAP Licensee** at TED Conferences, LLC 2015

# Clavinova ensemble national second place at Yamaha Mexico 2008

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

# **Intuitivity: Interaction in the cities** in PechaKucha Night Puebla Vol 5 20 February 2015

Intuitive. A natural ability or power that makes it possible to know something without any proof or evidence or a feeling that leads a person to act a certain way without fully understanding why.

# **Digital Notary** in Universidad de las Américas Puebla 17 May 2016

The aim of this paper is to present a proposal for the issuance of documents and digital files as legal instruments for the acceptance of acts or events where different actors can sign and can be authenticated.

#### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish	English	<b>Esperanto</b>
Native speaker	Advanced	Very Basic